BU Records: Baylor-Waco Foundation, Inclusive: 1949-2009, undated, Bulk: 1960-1994, undated
Baylor University Libraries
BU Records: Baylor-Waco Foundation
Inclusive: 1949-2009, undated, Bulk: 1960-1994, undated
Baylor University Libraries https://www.baylor.edu/library/
BU/43
Baylor-Waco Foundation; McKnight, Roy
2 document boxes and 2 oversized boxes.
BU Records: Baylor-Waco Foundation contains a variety of materials related to the fundraising efforts of the Foundation in order to benefit Baylor University and the City of Waco.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
The Baylor-Waco Foundation was initially organized by a group of forty Waco citizens in a meeting held 1959 December 9. The Foundation’s purpose, according to Article 4 of its Articles of Incorporation, is “to solicit funds and donations for and to plan and promote programs for the development and growth of Baylor University at Waco.”
The Foundation’s fundraising campaigns in the 1960s and early 1970s focused on raising money to purchase land for Baylor University through Waco’s Urban Renewal program. In the 1970s, 1980s, and early 1990s the Foundation turned its fundraising efforts towards construction and renovation projects on Baylor’s campus. These projects included developing the Baylor Marina, constructing the W. R. Poage Legislative Library, renovating the Marrs McLean Gymnasium, paving the parking lot of the Ferrell Center, providing lights for Ferrell Field, and resurfacing the Baylor Track. In the 1990s and 2000s, the Foundation shifted its focus towards projects that would benefit both Baylor and Waco, funding the acoustic shell at Waco Hall, a permanent home for Texas State Little League Headquarters, renovations to Armstrong Browning Library, a playground for Piper Child Development Center, a community meeting facility in the Harry & Anna Jeanes Discovery Center, a chapel lobby in the Stacy Riddle Forum, replacement flooring in Ferrell Center, underwriting a National Public Radio financial program, and providing visual enhancements for the Barfield Drawing Room.
The Baylor-Waco Foundation currently provides grant funding to “local non-profit organizations working in economic development, health, education, cultural wealth and city growth.” In 2020, the Foundation supplied grants totaling $90,000 to seven local non-profit organizations. The Foundation is also actively involved in Baylor’s Philanthropy & Public Good Course and the Solid Gold Neighbor Research Fellows Program.
Scope and Content
BU Records: Baylor-Waco Foundation consists of materials from 1949-2009, with some undated items. The collection reflects the fundraising efforts of the Foundation in order to benefit Baylor University and the City of Waco.
Series I. Administrative Files contains articles of incorporation and bylaws, meeting agenda and minutes, memos, publicity, advertisements, brochures, volunteer rosters, contributor lists, and two scrapbooks.
Arrangement
The collection was originally stored in two document boxes and two oversized boxes, with a scrapbook sitting on top of the two document boxes. The document boxes held folders organized chronologically within each box. One oversized box contained a scrapbook with handwritten and typed labels. The other oversized box contained a folder of newspaper ads and publicity arranged chronologically.
Currently, the collection contains a single series: I. Administrative Files. The level of processing deemed appropriate for this collection differs from other record groups at The Texas Collection. The collection remains in its original folders. Staples have been removed only in cases of obvious rust damage. The folders have been reorganized chronologically across the collection rather than merely within each box. The loose scrapbook was placed in the oversized box containing the second scrapbook. Personal information has been redacted.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/43. Acquired 1984-03-31
Related Resources
Related references
“Baylor/Waco Foundation.” Baylor University External Affairs. Accessed June 17, 2021.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Campus.; Baylor University.
Places
Waco (Tex.) -- Economic conditions.; Waco (Tex.).
Subjects
Baptist universities and colleges -- Texas -- Waco.; Campus planning -- Texas -- Waco.; Nonprofit organizations.
Genres
Advertisements.; By-laws.; Charters and articles of incorporation.; Memorandums.; Minutes (Records); Registers (Lists).; Scrapbooks.
- Administrative Files, 1949-2009, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  Series I. Administrative Files contains articles of incorporation and bylaws, meeting agenda and minutes, memos, publicity, advertisements, brochures, volunteer rosters, contributor lists, and two scrapbooks. The series is in average condition.
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation Minutes, 1949 May 6-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation Financial Affairs Office, 1960 December 31-1984 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1959-1961, 1961 January 8-December 7, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1962, 1961 November 12-1962 March 4, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1963, 1962 November 3-1963 November 12, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1964, 1964 February 3-2009 April 28, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1965, 1964 November 10-1965 September 16, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1966, 1966-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1968, 1967 November 28-1968 December 10, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1970, 1967 September 10-1973 February 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1971, 1970 September 14-1971 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1972, 1966 December 8-1973 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1973, 1972 September 10-1973 October 28, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1974, 1973 October 28-1974 November 21, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1975, 1974 December 5-1975 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baylor Waco Foundation 1976, 1964 May 31-1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation 1976-79, 1972 February 4-1979 January 31, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1977, 1977 January 27-December 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation 1980-84, 1980 February 8-1984 February 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation 1984, 1960 April-1993 April 23, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1984, 1984 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation, 1989-1990, 1989 January 26-1991 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation, 1991-1992, 1991 February 21-1992 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation, 1992-1993, 1978 February 24-1993 April 27, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1993-94, 1993 September 29-October 24 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 1994-95, 1994 October 29-November 10 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation 2002, 1990 February 20-2004 March 6, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation 2005, 2005 January 25-October (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation 2006, 2006 January 3-March (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Baylor/Waco Foundation, 2007 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation 2008, 2008 February-May (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Baylor-Waco FoundationDL1962 Green Scrapbook, 1957 April-1962 February 20, undated (Box [1058] OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Baylor-Waco Foundation Beige Scrapbook, 1961 December 17-1962 May 19, undated (Box [1058] OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Publicity, 1949 July 24-1978 April 30, undated (Box [1023] OVZ, Folder 1)